With stubborn conviction, I have decided
it is time to prepare for spring. Though
it will be many weeks before the snow is
completely gone, at least I can make
plans, do some late winter cleaning, and
enjoy the anticipation of a new season.
[Music]
Though it is still winter, the usually
icy morning smell is more subdued. The
roads are starting to get muddy and
change is in the air.
Today I'm cutting the last of the winter
squash and composting the seeds. I've
eaten so many squash seeds this year
that I don't think I'll be able to eat
more for a long while. Thankfully, they
can help feed my future garden.
[Music]
The coming month is a busy time. There
is much to be done. I'm patiently
waiting my seed catalog and will be
sharing my ambitious garden plans very
soon.
By the end of winter, I usually find
that a reorganization and tidy of my
home is in order. During the dark days,
I often let little tasks go undone,
having felt a bit sluggish during my
hibernation.
But now, the sun is shining a little
brighter. Winter is ever slowly
receding, and I of course am very
excited.
[Music]
When I lived in the city, while I was
aware of the seasons, I didn't
experience them in the same way I do
now. I noticed the cold weather and the
turning of the leaves, but that was
usually about it. Out here, it is a very
different experience. I observe the
coyote's winter mating season. The way
the deer wander much closer to my home
in January in search of food. The
usually rotund little quail are looking
thin this time of year since so much of
their body weight has been absorbed
simply to keep them warm and alive.
[Music]
The February full moon is known as the
hunger moon, representing the scarcity
animals and groups of people often
experienced at this time when their
reserves ran out. I find this particular
full moon very impactful, causing me to
reflect on the challenges that those
before me went through. It makes me
grateful for what I have and inspires me
to continue making little choices every
day to simplify my life, reuse items,
and reduce my waste. It feels like not
only a way to show my love to the earth,
but also to show reverence to others by
consuming only what I need to live
comfortably.
For example, I love decorating my home.
Instead of immediately buying a new
item, I look for secondhand decorations
or in this case make my own. The result
is usually very unique and special to
you.
[Music]